SARAH BERRY

I'm a seasoned web and print designer with 18 years of professionalism specializing in web development with a strong graphic design background. Experienced with all stages of the development process for dynamic web projects. Well versed in several CMS platforms with a keen eye on performance and accessibility with a long, successful track record in project management and customer relations.

401.368.1379

sb@sarahberryresume.com

DIGITAL PORTFOLIO SITE www.sarahberryresume.com

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE WEB DESIGNER

Motif Magazine — Pawtucket, RI

OCT 2017 - CURRENT

Overseeing and executing UI improvements to an array of WordPress sites associated with the magazine.

SENIOR DESIGNER

Envision Technology Advisors — Pawtucket, RI

OCT 2009 - SEPT 26, 2017

Architected web projects and online apps from initial discovery and planning through wireframing, design, build, QA, deployment, and client training using ExpressionEngine as our primary CMS platform. Also worked closely with marketing teams designing corporate logos & print pieces ranging from large-scale trade show graphics to corporate identity packages unifying our customers' online and offline aesthetics.

FREELANCE WEB DESIGNER

Self Employed — Pawtucket, RI

MAY 2007 - OCT 2009

Built a variety of ASP and PHP sites designed by Project Evolution in Providence RI and Solo Designs in Winchester MA. Designed, built and maintained sites for several of my own personal clients including Learning Links Educational Services, Chestnut Hill Studios, and several local artists and craftsman.

WEB DESIGNER/DEVELOPER/GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Envision Technology Advisors — Providence, RI

JUL 2001 - MAY 2007

My role at Envision during this time period was quite similar to the one I performed when I rejoined the company in 2009 (above). However there were more managerial duties required where I oversaw a team of web designers, the size of which, would fluctuate depending on project workload and scopes. Also designed for and heavily participated in running and planning a successful online marketing campaign for Amica Insurance.

WEB DESIGNER/DEVELOPER

New Media Advantage — Providence, RI

JUL 2000 - JUL, 2001

Designed, built, and maintained corporate sites, many of which were healthcare oriented. Managed a small team of developers, the scheduling of project milestones and coordinated with clients on proposed changes or challenges to be overcome. (*This company was acquired by Envision.*)

WEB DESIGNER/DEVELOPER

Metro Global Media Inc. — Cranston. RI

SEP 1999 - JUL. 2000

Designed, built, and maintained a large number of websites and online advertising for the "adult entertainment" industry. Collaborated with a team of third-party West Coast software engineers to create user interfaces for their e-commerce products.

PROJECT SAMPLES

Honey Dew Donuts

Designed and built their public site along with an intranet for employees and franchisees.

MTTI - Education for Employment

Designed their new site to be easy for them to update and to keep their programs current and success stories visually interesting.

Blackstone Valley Community Health Care

Redesigned their site to be cleaner, clearer, simple to update and translatable into several languages with an emphasis on ADA Compliance.

SKILLS

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- InDesign
- Dreamweaver
- Acrobat
- HTML5
- CSS3
- SCSS

- Git
- Google Analytics
- Balsamiq
- ExpressionEngine
- Wordpress
- MailChimp
- Constant Contact
- MS Office

ASSETS

- Creative Designs
- Responsive Builds
- Search Engine Optimization
- Accessibility/Usability Expertise
- Project & Client Management Skills
- Excellent Communicator
- Complex Problem Solver
- Strong Decision Maker
- Meticulous Attention to Detail

EDUCATION

RISD — BFA '99 | Majored in Illustration with a heavy leaning toward graphic design.